William J (Bo) McCarthy III, MSc

24511 Carlton Springs Lane Katy, TX 77494 Cell: (713) 806-3100 bomccarthy@yahoo.com

OBJECTIVE:

I seek a rewarding career position that allows me to utilize my experience and technology background along with my creative problem solving skills to effectively manage multiple assignments and promote team workmanship and effective leadership.

EXPERIENCE:

10/2011-6/2020, Geologist, Terra Nova Energy

- Manage day to day network and computer problems and issues.
- Implement strategic procedures for data migration and manipulation through programming.
- Reverse engineer software to evolve projects in an efficient manner based on network architecture.
- Organize storage server to maximize retrieval times for software speed.
- Create command driven files to automate time intensive workload.
- Served as technical support for internal user issues and data administrator for end users.
- Manage other employees while supervising computer hardware and software issues.

4/2010-5/2011, Senior Geotech, Apache Corporation, New Ventures Exploration

- Collaborate with IT to implement software necessary for department needs.
- Secure hardware and software resources needed to update project data
- Develop PowerPoint presentation materials for manager's and employee meetings.
- Risk analyze wells using Rose and Associates Excel software.

7/2002-4/2005, Information Technology/Data Processing, WJ Contracting

- Owner of self-perpetuating technical consulting business.
- Specialize in GIS, data management, graphical display and other computer issues.
- Develop general PC, network, email, and web maintenance routines.
- Focus on data process detailed with report creation, procedure writing, and form filing.

10/2000-6/2002, Installation Engineer, S1, Community & Regional eFinance Solutions Group

- Installation of hardware and software to IIS servers and workstations both internally and remotely.
- Preinstall, installation, training, and quality transition with the emphasis on customer service.
- Liaison between Programmers and Clients for specialized software distribution.
- Troubleshoot software or training issues for two months after installation completed.

EDUCATION:

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD), Expected completion Q3, 2022
Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA), Expected completion Q1, 2023
Master of Science, Geology, The University of Texas of the Permian Basin, May, 2013
Bachelor of Science, Geological Sciences, The University of Texas at Austin, May, 1998
Bachelor Credits toward Computer Science, The University of Texas at Austin, 1999-2000
Texas Real Estate License, TREC License #531594, Active Feb 2005-Feb 2017, Jul 2021-Pres

ACTIVITIES:

Member – West Texas Geological Society, July 2010-2020

President – AAPG Student Chapter of the Permian Basin, Fall 2010-Spring 2011

AAPG Committee Member – 2008-2013, Gulf Coast Section, AAPG Student Chapters Committee

OTC Committee Member – 2007-2011, The Next Wave Committee, AAPG Programs Committee

President – The University of Texas at Austin Chapter of the AAPG, Fall 1996-Spring 1998

Triathlon – 2005 Try Andy's Tri, 34th of 587, top 6%; Jeff and Brede's Tri, 3rd in Clydesdale Division